You're learning English, aren't you?
你正在学习英语，对吗？
You might think you can work out the grammar and have built up a vast vocabulary, but then you come across an expression like 'plos'.
你可能认为自己能够弄清楚语法，并且已经积累了大量的词汇，但随后你会遇到像“plos”这样的表达。
According to the online Urban Dictionary, it means 'parents looking over shoulder'.
根据在线的城市俚语词典，它的意思是“父母在背后偷看”。
You can blame teenagers for that.
这得怪青少年们。
They have a code of their own, including 'text speak' when they're online or using their phones.
他们有自己的暗语，包括在上网或使用手机时用的“文本语言”。
Text speak has a lot to do with inventing cool new terms - and these change quickly.
文本语言与发明很酷的新术语有很大关系——而且这些术语变化得很快。
Maybe you shouldn't be surprised if an English friend says you sound a bit old-fashioned.
如果一位英国朋友说你听起来有点老土，也许你不应该感到惊讶。
The modal verb 'shall' is on the way out because 'will' sounds more natural these days.
情态动词“shall”正逐渐过时，因为如今“will”听起来更自然。
Bas Aarts, Professor of English linguistics at University College London says, "If you have two words which more or less express the same meaning, one of the two words will get pushed out of the language."
伦敦大学学院的英语语言学教授巴斯·阿茨说：“如果你有两个或多或少表达相同意思的词，那么这两个词中的一个将会被挤出这种语言。”
People have been shying away from using the modal 'must' because it sounds authoritarian and people are choosing to express obligation in different ways.
人们一直避免使用情态动词“must”，因为它听起来很专横，而且人们正选择用不同的方式来表达责任。
It sounds nicer to soften obligation by saying 'might'.
用“might”来缓和义务的语气听起来更好。
For example, "You might like to read this article."
例如，“你或许会想读这篇文章。”
Progressive tenses - formed from the verb 'be' and the suffix 'ing' - are used for ongoing situations, for example, 'I'm writing this article for you to read'.
进行时态——由动词“be”和后缀“ing”构成——用于表示正在进行的情况，例如，“我正在写这篇文章供你阅读。”
But its use has been increasing rapidly.
但它的使用一直在迅速增加。
Bas Aarts says that this might have to do with advertising.
巴斯·阿茨说，这可能与广告有关。
A fast-food chain uses the expression 'I'm loving it' in English-speaking countries.
一家快餐连锁店在英语国家使用“我就喜欢”这种表达。
But the verb 'love' expresses a state of being - as opposed to doing - and is usually used in the simple form, for example, 'I love it'.
但是动词“love”表达的是一种状态——而不是动作——并且通常用一般现在时形式，例如，“我喜欢”。
These days, people are using stative verbs in the progressive more and more.
如今，人们越来越多地在进行时态中使用静态动词。
Before you despair and throw your English book in the bin, be assured that some words take a very long time to change.
在你绝望并把你的英语书扔进垃圾桶之前，请放心，有些单词需要很长时间才会发生变化。
According to Professor Mark Pagel at Reading University in the UK, pronouns like 'I', 'you' and 'we' evolve slowly - a thousand years ago we would be using similar or sometimes identical sounds.
根据英国雷丁大学的马克·佩格尔教授的说法，像“I”、“you”和“we”这样的代词变化得很慢——一千年前，我们使用的发音与之相似，有时甚至相同。
Nouns and adjectives, on the other hand, get replaced rapidly - and in 500 years or so we'll probably be using different words to the ones we have now.
另一方面，名词和形容词的更新换代却很快——大约500年后，我们可能会使用与现在不同的单词。
But let's leave that problem for the future generations.
但我们还是把这个问题留给后代吧。